Finding Aid for the Jonathan Friedlander Collection of Middle Eastern Americana LSC.1314
UCLA Library Special Collections
Jonathan Friedlander collection of Middle Eastern Americana
1875-2006
UCLA Library Special Collections
Friedlander, Jonathan
LSC.1314
16.5 Linear Feet (33 boxes)
21 oversize boxes.
Jonathan Friedlander, a scholar of Middle Eastern Studies and photographer of Americana began his personal collection of items documenting how Americans view the Middle East in 1971. The American Orientalism collection consists of photographic materials, pulp fiction, men's adventure magazines, comic books, audio and video recordings, advertisements, games, artifacts and objects, books, and sheet music.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
COLLECTION CONTAINS DIGITAL MATERIALS: Special equipment or further processing may be required for viewing. To access digital materials you must notify the reference desk in advance of your visit.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Jonathan Friedlander, 2006.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9960134093606533
Biography
Jonathan Friedlander, currently the assistant director of the UCLA Center for Near Eastern Studies, began to follow advertising and popular culture representations of the Middle East after moving to the United States in 1971. An Israel native, Friedlander started to collect a variety of popular culture publications and objects in earnest in the mid-1990s, in an effort to produce a collective representation of the way Americans view the Middle East.
Scope and Content
The collection includes photographic materials, pulp fiction, men's adventure magazines, comic books, audio and video recordings, advertisements, games, artifacts and objects, books, and sheet music that document American Orientalism in popular culture. The collection includes visual and topical content that evokes "the Orient," political and historical relationships between the East and West, gender stereotypes of "Oriental" or "Arab" men and women, as well as American advertising presentations of "Oriental" items as those of luxury.
Organization and Arrangement
The collection is arranged into ten series, five of which have been further arranged into subseries. Sound recordings, books, serials, sheet music, motion picture films, and Arabian Nights books are arranged alphabetically. The series and subseries arrangement is as follows:
Sound Recordings
Phonograph records
Compact discs
Books
[Books]
Children's books
Romance novels
Pocket-sized books
Serials
Pulp fiction
Comic books
Men's adventure magazines
Magazines
Advertisements
Games
Board games
Video games and manuals
Card games
Artifacts and Objects
Sheet Music
Motion Picture Films
Digital video discs (DVDs)
Laserdisks
VHS cassettes
Arabian Nights Books
Stereographs
Online Items Available
Portions of this collection have been digitized and are available online: Jonathan Friedlander Collection of Middle Eastern Americana (2669 items).
Middle East specialists -- California -- Los Angeles -- Archives.; Friedlander, Jonathan--Archives.
- Sound Recordings, 1950 - 2005; 5 oversize boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  This series consists of phonograph records (LPs) and compact discs (CDs) that document Middle Eastern artists or Orientalist perceptions of music and culture of the Middle East. The majority of the materials include sleeves and booklets of visual interest to the researcher interested in American Orientalism. The series includes belly dance music, classical interpretations of Scheherezade, motion picture soundtracks, and albums from popular musical performers.
  - Phonograph records, 1950 - 2003; 5 oversize boxes
    This subseries consists of LP records of multiple genres, including classical and popular music. Albums include music from Middle Eastern and American musicians, as well as dance compilations and soundtracks. Album sleeves are of great visual interest as the art and graphics displayed interpret the Middle East from a Western perspective.
    - Abu Hassan komische Oper in einem Akt Gesamtaufnahme Cologne: EMI Electrola., 1975; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Creator: Sawallisch, Wolfgang
      Role: conductor
    - Abu Hassan komische Oper in einem Akt Gesamtaufnahme Cologne: EMI Electrola., 1975; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo., 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Creator: Weber, Carl Maria von, 1786-1826
      Role: composer
    - Abu Hassan komische Oper in einem Akt Gesamtaufnahme Cologne: EMI Electrola., 1975; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo., 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Creator: Chor und Orchester der Bayerischen Staatsoper München
      Role: performer
    - Agatha Christie's death on the Nile Los Angeles, CA: Capitol., 1978; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo., 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Creator: Rota, Nino, 1911-
    - Aida United States: RCA Victor., 1962; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo., 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Creator: Solti, George
      Jacket excerpt reads, "The Khedive proclaimed Gloria all'Egitto, the big chorus of the Triumphal scene, the national anthem of Egypt."
    - Aida United States: RCA Victor., 1962; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo., 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Creator: Rome Opera House Orchestra and Chorus
    - Aida United States: RCA Victor., 1962; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo., 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Creator: Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901
    - Aida highlights London, England: London., 1959; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Cover is a photo of opera singer Renata Tebaldi.
    - Aida highlights London, England: London., 1959; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Creator: Karajan, Herbert von
    - Aida highlights London, England: London., 1959; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Creator: Vienna Philharmonic Orchestra
    - Aida opera-for-orchestra New York, NY: Columbia., 1955; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Creator: Kostelanetz, André
      Cover features a woman dressed in pharaonic royal costume.
    - Aida opera-for-orchestra New York, NY: Columbia., 1955; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Aida opera-for-orchestra New York, NY: Columbia., 1955; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Creator: Andre Kostelanetz Orchestra
    - Aida highlights Hollywood, CA: EMI Angel., 1975; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Cover photo by Louis Melançon.
    - Aida highlights Hollywood, CA: EMI Angel., 1975; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Aida highlights Hollywood, CA: EMI Angel., 1975; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Creator: Mehta, Zubin
    - André Kostelanetz conducts the music of Alan Hovhaness New York, NY: Columbia., 1977; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Creator: Hovhaness, Alan, 1911-
      Cover is a simulation of a Persian miniature.
    - André Kostelanetz conducts the music of Alan Hovhaness New York, NY: Columbia., 1977; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Creator: Kostelantez, André
    - André Kostelanetz conducts the music of Alan Hovhaness New York, NY: Columbia., 1977; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Creator: Gillot, Carol
      Role: illustrator
    - André Previn conducts Scheherazade New York, NY: RCA Gold Seal., 1976; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Creator: London Symphony Orchestra
      Cover art, featuring an illustration of King Shahryar and Scheherazade, by Ted Coconis.
    - André Previn conducts Scheherazade New York, NY: RCA Gold Seal., 1976; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Creator: Previn, André
    - André Previn conducts Scheherazade New York, NY: RCA Gold Seal., 1976; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Creator: Rimsky-Korsakov, Nikolai, 1844-1908
    - André Previn conducts Scheherazade New York, NY: RCA Gold Seal., 1976; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Creator: Coconis, Ted
    - Awakening San Francisco, CA: Entracte., 1980; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Creator: Bolling, Claude
      Cover features an illustration of a resurrected mummy. Album design by TerrificGraphics.
    - Baghdad Cafe soundtrack New York, NY: Great Jones., 1988; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Creator: Adlon, Percy, 1935-
    - Battle of Algiers original motion picture soundtrack Los Angeles, CA: United Artists., 1967; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Creator: Pontecorvo, Gillo
      Cover features a series of photographs from the film.
    - Battle of Algiers original motion picture soundtrack Los Angeles, CA: United Artists., 1967; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Creator: Nicolai, Bruno, 1926-
    - Battle of Algiers original motion picture soundtrack Los Angeles, CA: United Artists., 1967; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Creator: Morricone, Ennio
    - Bedouin belly dance New York, NY: P.I. Records., 1977; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Creator: Salim Sarweh Orchestra
      Jacket excerpt reads, "For thousands of years, the Bedouins' life has remained unchanged." Cover is a photo of belly dancer Nadira.
    - Bedouin belly dance New York, NY: P.I. Records., 1977; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Creator: Kassab, Youssef
    - Belly dance music New York, NY: Monitor., 1971; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Creator: Abdo, George
      Cover features a photograph of dancer Sultana Noga, by Tasso Mavris. Insert offers a belly dancing lesson with photographic illustration.
    - Belly dance music New York, NY: Monitor., 1971; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Creator: Flames of Araby Orchestra
    - Belly dance music from the Middle East New York, NY: Fiesta., ca. 1970s; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 14)
      Creator: Edward Mekjian Ensemble
      Cover design by Stephen Haas.
    - Belly dance music from the Middle East New York, NY: Fiesta., ca. 1970s; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 14)
      Creator: Mekjian, Eddie
    - Belly dancing for everyone New York, NY: Monitor., 1975; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Creator: Ensemble Sharqi
      Cover photo is a woman in belly dancing costume.
    - Belly dancing for everyone New York, NY: Monitor., 1975; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Creator: Kalogerson, Chris
    - Belshazzar's feast Hollywood, CA: Capitol., ca. 1960s.; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 16)
      Creator: Royal Philharmonic Orchestra
      Cover is a photo of an enraptured woman.
    - Belshazzar's feast Hollywood, CA: Capitol., ca. 1960s.; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 16)
      Creator: Wagner, Robert
    - Belshazzar's feast Hollywood, CA: Capitol., ca. 1960s.; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 16)
      Creator: Walton, William, 1902-
    - Belshazzar's feast New York, NY: Westminster., undated; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches, 2 copies (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Belshazzar's feast New York, NY: Westminster., undated; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches, 2 copies (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Creator: Boult, Adrian
    - Belshazzar's feast New York, NY: Westminster., undated; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches, 2 copies (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Creator: London Philharmonic Promenade Orchestra
    - Belshazzar's feast partita for orchestra New York, NY: Angel Records., 1958; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 18)
      Creator: Philharmonic Orchestra
    - Belshazzar's feast partita for orchestra New York, NY: Angel Records., 1958; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Belshazzar's feast partita for orchestra New York, NY: Angel Records., 1958; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Belshazzar's feast: improvisations on an impromptu of Benjamin Britten Hollywood, CA.: Capitol Records., 1972; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 19)
      Creator: Previn, Andre
      Cover is a photograph of a belly dancer's torso.
    - Belshazzar's feast: improvisations on an impromptu of Benjamin Britten Hollywood, CA.: Capitol Records., 1972; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Belshazzar's feast: improvisations on an impromptu of Benjamin Britten Hollywood, CA.: Capitol Records., 1972; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 19)
      Creator: London Symphonic Orchestra and Chorus
    - Ben-Hur Hollywood, CA: MGM., 1959; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 20)
      Creator: Savina, Carlo
      Cover includes images from motion picture.
    - Ben-Hur Hollywood, CA: MGM., 1959; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 20)
      Creator: Symphony Orchestra of Rome
    - Ben-Hur Hollywood, CA: MGM., 1959; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 20)
      Creator: Rózsa, Miklós, 1907-
    - Bible original motion picture soundtrack New York, NY: 20th Century-Fox Records., 1966; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 21)
      Creator: Ferrara, Franco
      Cover features photos of Michael Parks as Adam, Ulla Bergryd as Eve, George C. Scott as Abraham, Richard Harris as Cain and Franco Nero as Abel.
    - Bible original motion picture soundtrack New York, NY: 20th Century-Fox Records., 1966; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 21)
      Creator: Orchestra Cinefonica Italiana
    - Bible original motion picture soundtrack New York, NY: 20th Century-Fox Records., 1966; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 21)
      Creator: Chorus Carapellucci
    - Bible original motion picture soundtrack New York, NY: 20th Century-Fox Records., 1966; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 21)
      Creator: Mayuzumi, Toshiro, 1929-
    - Blues for Allah San Rafael, CA: Grateful Dead Records., 1975; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 22)
      Creator: Grateful Dead (Musical group)
      Album title written in arabicized English script. Liner notes includes translations of 'Blues for Allah' into Hebrew, Arabic, and Persian.
    - Blues for Allah San Rafael, CA: Grateful Dead Records., 1975; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 22)
      Creator: Hunter, Robert
    - Breathless Arista Records., 1978; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 23)
      Creator: Camel (Musical group)
      Sleeve design by Michael Munday and Cream.
    - Burning lights Camel Records., 1985; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 24)
      Creator: Sphinx (Musical group)
    - Caravans original motion picture score New York, NY: Epic., 1978; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 25)
      Creator: Batt, Mike
      Cover features a depiction of an Afghani caravan.
    - Caravans original motion picture score New York, NY: Epic., 1978; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 25)
      Creator: London Philharmonic Orchestra
    - Casablanca classic film scores for Humphrey Bogart New York, NY: RCA Victor., 1975; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 26)
      Creator: Waxman, Franz
      Cover is a photograph of Humphrey Bogart.
    - Casablanca classic film scores for Humphrey Bogart New York, NY: RCA Victor., 1975; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 26)
      Creator: Steiner, Max
    - Casablanca classic film scores for Humphrey Bogart New York, NY: RCA Victor., 1975; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 26)
      Creator: Young, Victor
    - Casablanca classic film scores for Humphrey Bogart New York, NY: RCA Victor., 1975; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 26)
      Creator: Hollander, Frederick
    - Casablanca classic film scores for Humphrey Bogart New York, NY: RCA Victor., 1975; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 26)
      Creator: National Philharmonic Orchestra
    - Casablanca classic film scores for Humphrey Bogart New York, NY: RCA Victor., 1975; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 26)
      Creator: Gerhardt, Charles
    - Casablanca classic film scores for Humphrey Bogart New York, NY: RCA Victor., 1975; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Casablanca classic film scores for Humphrey Bogart New York, NY: RCA Victor., 1975; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 26)
      Creator: Rózsa, Miklós
    - Cast a giant shadow, original motion picture score New York, NY: United., 1966; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 27)
      Creator: Bernstein, Elmer
    - Choice quality stuff New York, NY: Columbia., 1971; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 28)
      Creator: It's a Beautiful Day (Musical group)
      Sleeve design by George Bennett. Features an illustration of an intoxicated camel in front of pyramids.
    - Cleopatra, the original soundtrack recording from the motion picture New York, NY: 20th Century-Fox Records., 1963; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 1, Folder 29)
      Creator: North, Alex
      Cover is a painting of Elizabeth Taylor as Cleopatra, Richard Burton as Marc Antony and Rex Harrison as Julius Caesar.
    - Cole Porter's Aladdin New York, NY: Columbia., 1958; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Creator: Bennett, Robert Russell
      Jacket excerpt reads, "When it comes to opulence of the imagination, there is practically nothing that can approach the Arabian Nights, and the same might be said of Cole Porter and S.J. Perleman. Each, in his way, is as reliable a sorcerer as one might find roaming around old Baghdad..."
    - Desert song and Roberta Hollywood, CA: Capitol., ca. 1950s; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 inches (Box 2, Folder 2)
      Creator: Romberg, Sigmund, 1887-1951
    - Desert song and Roberta Hollywood, CA: Capitol., ca. 1950s; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 inches (Box 2, Folder 2)
      Creator: Greeley, George
    - Desert song and Roberta Hollywood, CA: Capitol., ca. 1950s; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 inches (Box 2, Folder 2)
      Creator: Kern, Jerome, 1885-1945
    - Dramatic highlights and love themes from Solomon and Sheba New York, NY: United., 1954; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 in (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Creator: Nascimbene, Mario
      Cover is a photo of Yul Brynner and Gina Lollobrigida as Solomon and Sheba.
    - East of Suez Media, PA: Somerset., ca. 1960s; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 2, Folder 4)
      Creator: Miller, D. L.
      Cover is a photograph of a woman dressed as a harem girl. Jacket excerpt reads, "From the brilliant and scintillating percussive effects that depict the busy bazaars in Baghdad to the sensuous woodwinds that take us to the forbidden halls of the Temple Dancers - these are the moods and sounds that portray the fascinating ports and places of our sojourn in music."
    - El debke: music of the Middle East New York, NY: Audio Fidelity., 1962; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 2, Folder 5)
      Creator: Agby, Naif
      Cover photo is a belly dancer's torso. Excerpt from liner notes reads, "Throughout the daylight hours, the suk is thronged with men, boys and a few heavily veiled women."
    - Element of light Watford, England: Glass Fish Records., 1986; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 2, Folder 6)
      Creator: Robyn Hitchcock and the Egyptians (Musical group)
      Cover photograph by Rosalind Kunath.
    - Element of light Watford, England: Glass Fish Records., 1986; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 2, Folder 6)
      Creator: Hitchcock, Robyn
    - Essar Hollywood, CA: Tamla., 1984; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 2, Folder 7)
      Creator: Robinson, Smokey, 1940-
      Cover is a photograph of Smokey Robinson with an Egyptian sarcophagus in the background.
    - Exodus New York, NY: United Artists., 1961; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 2, Folder 8)
      Creator: Gold, Ernest, 1921-
    - Exodus original sound track New York, NY: United Artists., 1960; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 2, Folder 9)
      Creator: Sinfonia of London
    - Exodus original sound track New York, NY: United Artists., 1960; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Exotic dances of the Middle East New York, NY: London International., ca. 1960s; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 in (Box 2, Folder 10)
      Creator: Derbecki Ensemble
      Cover photo is a woman in belly dancing costume. Back cover provides a belly dancing lesson.
    - Exotic dances of the Middle East New York, NY: London International., ca. 1960s; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 in (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Exotic dances of the Middle East New York, NY: London International., ca. 1960s; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 in (Box 2, Folder 10)
      Creator: Peters, Laurice
    - Film music of Miklós Rózsa North Hollywood, CA: Varèse Sarabande., 1979; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Flame of Araby: music of the Middle East New York, NY: Des Records., ca. 1960s; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 2, Folder 12)
      Creator: Agby, Olga
      Cover art features a photograph of Lorraine Shalhoub in belly dancing costume. In the background is a seated, veiled woman smoking a water pipe.
    - Flame of Araby: music of the Middle East New York, NY: Des Records., ca. 1960s; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Folk songs by the Karmon Israeli singers and dancers New York, NY: Vanguard., ca. 1960s; 1 sound disc: analog, 33 1/3 rpm, stereo, 12 inches (Box 2, Folder 13)
      Creator: Folk Instrument Orchestra
      Cover features a photo of the Karmon Israeli Dance Company. Jacket excerpt reads, "Young voices, young songs and a young culture have produced this program, which represents one of the fine artistic fruits of the State of Israel, founded in 1948...this stream of song draws upon age-old traditions and also constantly reshapes them, so that they embody the spirit of the pioneering population."